<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bioinformatics on JUNPENG ZHANG</title>
    <link>https://zhangjunpeng411.github.io/tags/bioinformatics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bioinformatics on JUNPENG ZHANG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Junpeng Zhang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/bioinformatics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA sponge</title>
      <link>https://zhangjunpeng411.github.io/project/mirna_sponge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhangjunpeng411.github.io/project/mirna_sponge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent studies have discovered that miRNA sponges are closely associated with the
occurrence and development of cancers, and it is a significant and challenging
subject to study the mechanisms of miRNA sponges in cancers. From the perspective
of systems biology, this subject integrates heterogeneous biological data
including high throughput data, such as miRNA, lncRNA, mRNA, pseudogene and
circRNA expression profiles, miRNA-target databases, and genes-disease
relationship databases, to study the identification and reconfirmation of cancer
miRNA sponges, the causal relationships between cancer miRNA sponges, and new
methods and technologies of miRNA, lncRNA, mRNA, pseudogene and circRNA expression
data analysis. The aim is to identify cancer-related miRNA sponges and miRNA
sponge causal networks and modules in cancers, and further develop a
bioinformatics analysis software package for inferring miRNA sponge causal
networks and modules in cancers. By combining molecular function databases (GO,
KEGG, etc.), we apply the methods into Pan-Cancer data analysis including 12
disease types to mine cancer-conserved and specific miRNA sponge causal networks
and modules. The research results will be of great importance in exploring the
pathogenesis mechanisms of cancers, and promoting the study on precision medicine
of human cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
